Israel Agyeman-Prempeh

Senior Software Engineer

Email israel.agyeman.prempeh@gmail.com Phone +447908610803

Versatile full-stack developer specialising in front-end technologies with added skill in UI/UX design. I have over 8 years of experience in FinTech, architecting UIs that handle extensive, high-frequency data. Most of my work is in JavaScript, Typescript, React for the front-end and Python for the backend. A curious learner willing to take on new challenges, and work within high-functioning teams while bringing on my garnered expertise and delivering high-performance products to fulfil business needs

Professional Experience

2023-07 - present

Associate Director - Senior Software Engineer Core UI

RBC Capital Markets, London

- Global UI Lead driving the development and maintenance of RBC Capital Markets' core UI libraries, including MUI-based components, an AG Grid extension, and an Apache ECharts-based charting library, all widely adopted across the organization.
- Implemented high-quality CLI tools for building, testing, templating, and module federation, leveraging technologies like Rspack, Nx custom executors, and SWC to abstract complex configurations and accelerate development.
- Overhauled dependency management using Nx monorepos, streamlining CI/CD pipelines with custom scripts, Docker and integrating firm-wide DevOps strategies via GitHub Actions and Jenkins for semantic versioning compliance.
- Built a Dev portal to reduce the barrier of entry to from idea to prototype with developer experience at the fore-front
- Architected a roadmap and Prioritized tasks to modernize UI libraries with cutting-edge frontend technologies, including module-federation and VSCode Extensions

2022-07 - 2023-07

Vice President - Rates Flow Technology

Bank of America, London

- Designed, architected, and implemented performant UI handling thousands of live-ticking data used by traders and middle-office, using efficient paradigms in JavaScript; web workers, WebSockets and Typescript
- UI Lead on unified trading and trade-blotter application used by sales and traders. Work included RFQ terminals with live risk and market data
- · Spearheaded UI reconstruction of legacy python application, leading a team of engineers
- Handled releases SDLC and CI/CD pipelines as an additional role while managing releases and interfacing with senior leadership on state of production

2016-07 - 2022-02

Assistant Vice President - Rates Flow Technology

Bank of America, London

• Led the transformation of a legacy supervisory tool by rebuilding its UI from Python to a modern, ReactJS-

• Designed and developed intuitive UI/UX wireframes and implemented robust RESTful and WebSocket APIs using Tornado. The revamped application's success drove its global adoption, consolidating all supervisory tools into a unified platform and establishing it as the bank's primary supervisory solution.

2015-06 - 2015-08

Summer Technology Intern

Bank of America Merrill Lynch, London

• Designed UI concept and implemented a UI framework with pre-built components using Jade and AngularJS to allow backend developers to build quick and easy UIs with minimal code.

Education

2012-09 - 2016-06

Computer Science 3.58/4.0, B.Sc. (Cum Laude)

Ashesi University College, Accra-Ghana

Skills

Javascript: Typescript, React, Openfin/Electron, Webworkers, RsPack, cli tools

DevOps: Github Actions, Jenkins, Artifactory, Nx Monorepos, Docker

UI/UX Design and Wireframing: AxureRP, Photoshop, Illustrator, Blender3D

Projects

2016-01 - 2016-04

Capstone Project

Smart Home Surveillance and Intelligent Traffic Light System

Built home surveillance and smart traffic light system which employed computer vision with Histogram-of-Oriented-Gradients for human detection

Volunteering

Africa and Campus Recruitment Program - Bank of America

Mentored and helped coordinate campus recruitment efforts within Bank of America technology with a focus on African and London university candidates. This program was overseen by the CTO.